Muhammad Faizan

CONTACT

Islamabad, Pakistan

E-mail: mohammadfaizan980@gmail.com

Phone: +923419299464

DESCRIPTION

An app developer and a designer with over 3.5 years of development experience with proven

tendency to learn and adapt to new technologies in record time.

I work in both, Native Android (Kotlin) and Flutter App Development.

I have tendency to learn and adapt new things quickly. For example, I learned Node.js when I needed to work on some APIs, learned Figma when needed to demonstrate a UI concept with prototype, learned Strapi when a project required me for that, learned SDUI when a project needed and many more examples.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Infusible Coder

Feb, 2019 — Mar, 2021

Flutter/Android Developer

Worked as a native android and flutter developer and worked on variety of apps mainly using google maps, InApp payments, stripe, REST APIs, Firebase services

tentwenty digital agency

Mar, 2021 — Feb, 2022

Flutter Developer

Worked here as full time flutter developer and partially backend dev using Strapi

SafariOne

Feb, 2022 — Present

App Developer (Flutter + Kotlin)

Currently working here as a full time app developer, working a native android app using jetpack compose, app will connect with vending machines for providing POS services using serial communication with the vending machine and also raspberryPi connection for machines which do not allow direct communication with internal hardware. Along with that, I am also working on a flutter app for the hosts, who will provide their property for hosting the vending machine for public use. Also sometimes doing UI/UX designing and prototyping.

PREVIOUS WORK

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.tentwenty.whocares Whocares allows people to stay in touch with your loved ones. You can update your status, create your spaces and invite people via link, you can ask a person for their status and more.

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.apps.brainer_book App to help train your brain and improve your memory.

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.thampy.dfsa
Official DFSA app to stay in touch with their news and announcements and enquiry.

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=mgks.os.jumpi South African govt app for entrepreneurs and to help them in their journey by keeping them in engaged with via podcasts and more.

Muhammad Faizan

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.aramco.saudi.pavilion Saudi Pavilion management app for Dubai Expo 2020 for VIP management.

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.apps.amass
An app for keeping your brain healthy, you can create your classes, add items to them, keep track of your progress and so on.

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.org.lsuk Employees management app for LSUK (UK based company)

SKILLS

- Flutter
- Dart
- Kotlin
- Jetpack Compose
- MVVM
- Providers
- Stacked
- Location Services
- Rest APIs
- SQLite using Drift and Floor for Flutter, Room for native
- RabbitMQ (native)
- SDUI
- Google Maps
- Leaflet.js Maps aka Flutter Map
- Firebase (storage, auth, social auth, firestore, realtime DB)
- Bluetooth Communication
- Sockets

EDUCATION

Matric	2012 — 2014
FSC Fazaia Inter College, Kohat	2014 — 2016
Kohat University of Science and Technology	2010 2020
BSCS	2016 — 2020

INTERESTS

Gym, Hiking, Cricket, Tourism

FG Public High School, Kohat

REFERENCES

References available upon request.

Muhammad Faizan 2